{"message":
    [
        {
            "question": "What is data science?",
            "answer": "Data science is the study of data to extract meaningful insights for business. It is a multidisciplinary approach that combines principles and practices from the fields of mathematics, statistics, artificial intelligence, and computer engineering to analyze large amounts of data. This analysis helps data scientists to ask and answer questions like what happened, why it happened, what will happen, and what can be done with the results."
        },
        {
            "question": "Why is data science important?",
            "answer": "Data science is important because it combines tools, methods, and technology to generate meaning from data. Modern organizations are inundated with data; there is a proliferation of devices that can automatically collect and store information. Online systems and payment portals capture more data in the fields of e-commerce, medicine, finance, and every other aspect of human life. We have text, audio, video, and image data available in vast quantities."
        },
        {
            "question": "History of data science",
            "answer": "While the term data science is not new, the meanings and connotations have changed over time. The word first appeared in the ’60s as an alternative name for statistics. In the late ’90s, computer science professionals formalized the term. A proposed definition for data science saw it as a separate field with three aspects: data design, collection, and analysis. It still took another decade for the term to be used outside of academia."
        },
        {
            "question": "Future of data science",
            "answer": "Artificial intelligence and machine learning innovations have made data processing faster and more efficient. Industry demand has created an ecosystem of courses, degrees, and job positions within the field of data science. Because of the cross-functional skillset and expertise required, data science shows strong projected growth over the coming decades."
        },
        {
            "question": "What is data science used for?",
            "answer": "Data science is used to study data in four main ways: 1. Descriptive analysis: Descriptive analysis examines data to gain insights into what happened or what is happening in the data environment. It is characterized by data visualizations such as pie charts, bar charts, line graphs, tables, or generated narratives. 2. Diagnostic analysis: Diagnostic analysis is a deep-dive or detailed data examination to understand why something happened. It is characterized by techniques such as drill-down, data discovery, data mining, and correlations. 3. Predictive analysis: Predictive analysis uses historical data to make accurate forecasts about data patterns that may occur in the future. It is characterized by techniques such as machine learning, forecasting, pattern matching, and predictive modeling. 4. Prescriptive analysis: Prescriptive analytics takes predictive data to the next level. It not only predicts what is likely to happen but also suggests an optimum response to that outcome."
        },
        {
            "question": "What are the benefits of data science for business?",
            "answer": "Data science is revolutionizing the way companies operate. Many businesses, regardless of size, need a robust data science strategy to drive growth and maintain a competitive edge. Some key benefits include: Discover unknown transformative patterns, Innovate new products and solutions, Real-time optimization."
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the data science process?",
            "answer": "A business problem typically initiates the data science process. A data scientist will work with business stakeholders to understand what business needs. Once the problem has been defined, the data scientist may solve it using the OSEMN data science process: Obtain data, Scrub data, Explore data, Model data, Interpret results."
        },
        {
            "question": "What are the data science techniques?",
            "answer": "Data science professionals use computing systems to follow the data science process. The top techniques used by data scientists are: Classification, Regression, Clustering."
        },
        {
            "question": "What are different data science technologies?",
            "answer": "Data science practitioners work with complex technologies such as: Artificial intelligence, Cloud computing, Internet of things, Quantum computing."
        },
        {
            "question": "How does data science compare to other related data fields?",
            "answer": "Data science is an all-encompassing term for other data-related roles and fields. While the terms data science and data analytics may be used interchangeably, data analytics is a subset of data science. Data science is an umbrella term for all aspects of data processing—from the collection to modeling to insights. On the other hand, data analytics is mainly concerned with statistics, mathematics, and statistical analysis. It focuses on only data analysis, while data science is related to the bigger picture around organizational data."
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the difference between data science and data engineering?",
            "answer": "Data engineers build and maintain the systems that allow data scientists to access and interpret data. They work more closely with underlying technology than a data scientist. The role generally involves creating data models, building data pipelines, and overseeing extract, transform, load (ETL). Data scientists use the data that data engineers have processed to build and train predictive models. Data scientists may then hand over the results to the analysts for further decision making."
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the difference between data science and machine learning?",
            "answer": "Machine learning is the science of training machines to analyze and learn from data the way humans do. It is one of the methods used in data science projects to gain automated insights from data. Machine learning engineers specialize in computing, algorithms, and coding skills specific to machine learning methods. Data scientists might use machine learning methods as a tool or work closely with other machine learning engineers to process data."
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the difference between data science and statistics?",
            "answer": "Statistics is a mathematically-based field that seeks to collect and interpret quantitative data. In contrast, data science is a multidisciplinary field that uses scientific methods, processes, and systems to extract knowledge from data in various forms. Data scientists use methods from many disciplines, including statistics. However, the fields differ in their processes and the problems they study."
        },
        {
            "question": "What are different data science tools?",
            "answer": "AWS has a range of tools to support data scientists around the globe: Data storage, Machine learning, Analytics."
        },
        {
            "question": "What does a data scientist do?",
            "answer": "A data scientist can use a range of different techniques, tools, and technologies as part of the data science process. Based on the problem, they pick the best combinations for faster and more accurate results."
        },
        {
            "question": "What are the challenges faced by data scientists?",
            "answer": "Data scientists face multiple challenges including: Multiple data sources, Understanding the business problem, Elimination of bias."
        },
        {
            "question": "How to become a data scientist?",
            "answer": "There are usually three steps to becoming a data scientist: Earn a bachelor's degree in IT, computer science, math, physics, or another related field. Earn a master's degree in data science or related field. Gain experience in a field of interest."
        }

    ]
}